press.net 2014-06-30

# Privacy policy

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect about you as a user of our websites (a “ **Site** ”) and our services, how this information is used, and how you can opt-out of certain types of processing. In the UK, we operate and are registered in accordance with applicable data protection legislation. ****

**By using the Site and our services you are consenting to the use of your personal information as set out in this Privacy Policy and cookies to be placed on your computer.**

This Privacy Policy covers:

Who we are

Changes to the Privacy Policy and Queries

What personal information we collect about you and why

Our use of personal information for marketing purposes 

Disclosure of personal data to third parties

How we use cookies and similar technology

Links to other websites

Storage of your data and international transfers

Data security

How to contact us  

 **Who are we?  
**  
The Press Association Limited is the owner of this Site, and is a member of the PA Group.

*PA Group means PA Group Limited and any other company which is more than 50% owned or controlled by PA Group Limited (company number 4197) or any of its wholly owned subsidiaries (such as The Press Association Limited, PA Photos Limited or PA Sport UK Limited).

**Changes to the Privacy Policy and Queries**

If we make changes to this Privacy Policy in the future, these will be posted on this page so please do check back from time to time.

Any questions regarding our Privacy Policy should be directed to our Data Protection Officer. Please see the section ‘How to contact us’ [2]below.

This Privacy Policy covers the following Sites:

Pressassociation.com  
  
---  
  
paimages.co.uk  
  
empicsentertainment.co.uk  
  
Communitynewswire.press.net  
  
Pafeaturefile.com  

Premierfootball.pa-sport.com  
  
Pa-mediapoint.press.net  
  
Mediapoint.press.net  
  
Mediapointscotland.press.net  
  
Mediapointireland.press.net  
  
Mediapointhealth.press.net  
  
Mediapoint.resource.press.net  
  
Medialawyer.press.net  
  
Picselect.com  
  
Premiershowbiz.co.uk  
  
Luxuryfinance.com  
  
Mediafinance.com  
  
Satellitefinance.com  
  
Telecomfinance.com  
  
<http://pads.pa-sport.com/api/football>  
  
<http://pads.pa-sport.com/api/olympics>  
  
**What personal information do we collect and why?  
**  
We may collect personal information from you (such as your name, address, telephone number, email address etc) when you complete registration or enquiry forms or send emails to us, so that we may provide you with the services and information which you request. Please do not submit your personal information to us if you do not wish us to collect it.

If you login or subscribe to any PA Group service or product, we will use your personal information to provide you with the service or product you select, (e.g. sending you password reminders or notices about the relevant service or product being suspended for emergency or routine maintenance).

If you purchase services and products from us we may also need your name, address and payment information in order to process your transaction.

We may collect information if you choose to post information to the Site in the form of comments or contributions to discussions. In addition, we may collect information from you, for example, in order to reply to any enquiry you make of any PA Group company or notify you of a change to our service. We may also use the information you provide for our own internal statistical purposes.

You are under no obligation to provide any such information. However, if you should choose to withhold requested information, we may not be able to provide you with certain services.

 **Use of your personal information for marketing purposes  
**  
We may, with your agreement, give your personal information to other companies within the PA Group, for the purposes of providing products and services you have requested from us and so that those group companies can provide you with information relating to products and services we think may interest you, by letter, email or on your mobile device.

If you do not wish to receive this promotional material, you may opt-out at any time by:

  * notifying your usual PA Group contact;      or
  * sending an e-mail      or [writing      to us](http://www.pressassociation.com/privacy-policy.html#howtocontactus) telling us you do not wish to receive further promotional      material; or
  * using the "unsubscribe"      process described in the promotional material.

**Disclosure of personal information to third parties  
**  
We will not disclose any personal information you provide to us to any third party organisation outside the PA Group of companies, unless:

  * we need to do so to provide you with the      products or services you select, for example where we use service      providers to provide certain services in support of the Site;
  * we are obliged or permitted by law to      disclose it (for example if required by law or a court order ); 
  * we sell or buy or reorganise any business      or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the      reorganised entity or the prospective seller or buyer of such business or      assets;
  * a PA Group company or substantially all      of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data      held by it may be one of the transferred assets; 
  * to protect the rights, property, or      safety of any PA Group company, its customers, employees, or others. This      includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for      the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction; or
  * the information is only in the form of      aggregate statistics about visitors to the Site in order to describe our      services to prospective partners, advertisers, sponsors and other      reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes and which contain no      personally identifiable information.

**Use of cookies and similar technology  
**  
Cookies are text files stored by your browser software that identify your device to the cookie owner's server. We use cookies to remember you when you visit the Site or other services that we provide to you. There are two main types of cookies that we use:

(a)      ‘ **Session’** cookies – where they only last for the duration of your browser session and expire when you close it.

(b)      ‘ **Remember Me’** cookies (aka “Persistent” cookies) - cookies that remain on your computer after you close your browser and computer to remember you when you return to the Site. These can last from 30 minutes to years.

We use cookies to:

  * obtain statistical information about your general internet usage and build up a profile of how you and others use the Site, and to improve our Site and deliver a better service to you;
  * remember your session so that you can move from one page to another within the Site;
  * store your preferences; and ****
  * in the case of the pads.pa-sport.com Sites, customise elements of the layout and/or content of the pages of the Site for you once you have submitted the PA unique API key.   ****

We do not use cookies to store your credit or debit card details. ****

_You can remove cookies from your Browser:_

Most web browsers are set up to automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting, you may be unable to use the full functionality of the Site and your user experience may be adversely affected. You can learn more about cookies by visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) which includes additional information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browser.

A simple guide to removing cookies is to go to the “Tools” option in your web browser options, select “Settings”. To delete all cookies on your computer to date select “Clear Browsing History” and to set options for future cookies select “Cookies” and the options you wish to apply to your web browser. 

a)    _Our cookies_

We use the following cookies:

**Cookie name**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Type and   duration**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Pressassociation.com

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions ****

| 

Session  
  
| 

Anonymous reporting of patterns of activity and usage   statistics on the site to manage demand using Google Analytics

| 

Remember me for 2 years  
  
empicsentertainment.co.uk

| 

Anonymous reporting of patterns of activity and usage   statistics on the site to manage demand using Google Analytics

| 

Remember me for 2 years  
  
Communitynewswire.press.net

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Pafeaturefile.com

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Premierfootball.pa-sport.com

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Pa-mediapoint.press.net

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Mediapoint.press.net

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Mediapointscotland.press.net

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Mediapointireland.press.net

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Mediapointhealth.press.net

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Mediapoint.resource.press.net

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Picselect.com

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Premiershowbiz.co.uk

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Luxuryfinance.com

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Mediafinance.com

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Satellitefinance.com

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
Telecomfinance.com

| 

Only used for maintaining login sessions

| 

Session only  
  
<http://pads.pa-sport.com/api/olympics>****

| 

Domain level to store the API Key when accessing the online documentation for delivery   of the content requested

| 

Remember me for 1 year  
  
<http://pads.pa-sport.com/api/football>****

| 

Domain level to store the API Key when accessing the online documentation for delivery   of the content requested

| 

Remember me for 1 year  
  
b)    _Third party cookies_

Cookies are also set by third parties on the Site (such as Google Analytics). 

We don't have access to these cookies. We only allow them to be served. However, we may use the statistical information provided to us by our partners arising from these third party cookies, for example, to improve the targeting of advertisements to users of the Site.

The third parties that generate these cookies and action tags have their own privacy policies describing how they use the information that they collect.  More information about cookies placed by specific third parties and how to restrict or block their cookies can be accessed by following the link to their website and to generate an "opt-out" cookie that will stop any further cookies being written to your device. You can also visit the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) website at [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) **** for information on how to obtain an "opt-out cookie" from other third parties.

**Cookie name**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Type and   duration**

| 

**How to reject   or delete this cookie**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Google Analytics_utma

| 

Identifying Unique   Visitors: the cookie records the browser used to visit the Site and not the   individual visiting the Site. It also logs how many times the browser has   visited this Site, unless the cookies are deleted by you. There is no   individual’s data recorded.

| 

Remember Me for 2 years

| 

Go to <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>   and follow the steps  
  
Google Analytics_utmb

| 

Determining Visitor   Session: requires combined user with _utmc for functionality.  Tracks a “session” on the Site. Refreshes   each time you move webpage in your browser. Records no individual’s data.

| 

Remember Me for 30 minutes

| 

Go to <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>   and follow the steps  
  
Google Analytics_utmc

| 

Determining Visitor   Session: requires combined user with _utmb for functionality. Tracks a   “session” on the Site. Records no individual’s data.

| 

Session upon closing   browser

| 

Go to <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>   and follow the steps  
  
Google Analytics_utmz

| 

Trafficking traffic,   sources and navigation (aka campaign cookie): cookie stores the referral   information when landing on the Site from a web search or third party link   and where you visit within the Site after landing on the Site. Records no   individual’s data.

| 

Remember Me for 6 months

| 

Go to <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>   and follow the steps  
  
If you would like to know more about Google Analytics cookies please visit: <http://www.google.com/analytics/iq.html>__

**Links to other websites**

This Site may contain links to other websites which are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Please note that, if you access other websites using the links provided, the operators of these websites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours.

**Storage of your data and international transfers**

Information that you submit via the Site is sent to and stored on secure servers located in the UK, the Netherlands and Ireland and your information is processed in accordance with European data protection law.  However your information may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”).  By way of example, this may happen if one or more of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside the EEA or one of our service providers or group companies is located in a country outside the EEA.  If we transfer your information outside the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected.

In addition, if you use our services while you are outside the EEA, your information may be transferred outside the EEA in order to provide you with those services.

**Data Security  
**  
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers or in secure filing systems.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to us via the internet; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

 **How to contact us  
**  
If you have any queries with regard to our data processing practices or you wish to correct or update or request a copy of any of the personal details we hold about you, please contact your usual PA Group contact or send us an email or write to us at: The Data Protection Officer, Legal Department, The Press Association Limited, 292 Vauxhall Bridge Road, London SW1V 1AE. 

Any request for a copy of information may be subject to a fee (currently £10) to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we may hold about you.

 **  
**.

* * *

[1] These headings should be hyperlinks to the relevant sections

[2] Make this an active link to the ‘contacting us’ section
